Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine UP040
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine
2005 -- 2013
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of the Dean of the School of Medicine
UP040
0.5 Linear Feet
29 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized in one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine e-newsletter started in June 2005. It was created as an e-newsletter to improve communication within the Medical School community. The publication schedule for the Dean's Letter is nine times per year. This collection consists of PDF versions of the Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine. At this time, the March, 2007 issue is missing.
Biographical / Historical
The Medical School and Dental School were jointly administered by one Dean until 1914, when the Office of the Vice-Dean was created in the Medical School. The Dental School added its own Vice-Dean in 1915, and then in 1917 appointed its own Dean, thereby separating the administration of the two schools. The Medical School was renamed the School of Medicine in 1954 when Tufts College became Tufts University.
Subsequently, the Office of the Dean has been involved in numerous transitional processes for the continuously expanding School of Medicine. Particularly, Deans have been involved in the creation and administration of the Tufts Medical Center as it has gradually acquired additional facilities and resources in the downtown area.
The Office of the Dean of the School of Medicine administers the academic departments, student services, and facilities of the Tufts University School of Medicine, and supervises the School's teaching and research activities. The Office of the Dean performs a variety of tasks to fulfill its larger objectives, such as recruitment of new faculty and strategic and financial planning.
- Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2005 -- 2013; UP040.001; 0.5 Linear Feet; 29 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  The Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine e-newsletter started in June 2005. It was created as an e-newsletter to improve communication within the Medical School community. The publication schedule for the Dean's Letter is nine times per year.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2005-06; UP040.001.001.00001; School of Medicine
    No volume or issue information.
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2005-08; UP040.001.001.00002; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2005-09; UP040.001.001.00003; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2005-11; UP040.001.001.00004; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2005-12; UP040.001.001.00005; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2006-02; UP040.001.001.00006; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2006-03; UP040.001.001.00007; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2006-05; UP040.001.001.00008; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2006-06; UP040.001.001.00009; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2006-08; UP040.001.001.00010; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2006-09; UP040.001.001.00011; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2006-11; UP040.001.001.00012; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2006-12; UP040.001.001.00013; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2007-01; UP040.001.001.00014; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2007-03; UP040.001.001.00015; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2007-05; UP040.001.001.00016; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2007-06; UP040.001.001.00017; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2007-08; UP040.001.001.00018; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2007-10; UP040.001.001.00019; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2007-12; UP040.001.001.00020; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2008-02; UP040.001.001.00021; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2008-04; UP040.001.001.00022; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2008-06; UP040.001.001.00023; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2008-08; UP040.001.001.00024; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2008-10; UP040.001.001.00025; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2009-01; UP040.001.001.00026; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2009-03; UP040.001.001.00027; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2009-06; UP040.001.001.00028; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2009-08; UP040.001.001.00029; School of Medicine
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2011-11; UP040.001.002.00001; School of Medicine (Box 2)
  - Dean's Letter for Tufts Medicine, 2013-09; UP040.001.002.00002; School of Medicine (Box 2)